Guide to the Loma Prieta earthquake collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Loma Prieta earthquake collection
1989-1990
SC0566
Stanford University
1.75 Linear feet
This collection of various materials concerning the effect of the October 17, 1989, earthquake includes press releases from the Stanford University News Service, photographs of interior and exterior damage to Stanford buildings, slides (approx. 180) of damage to and repairs done at the museum, personal accounts from university staff and students, miscellaneous university newsletters with quake-related stories, and special editions of assorted newspapers.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
This collection of various materials concerning the effect of the October 17, 1989, earthquake includes press releases from the Stanford University News Service, photographs of interior and exterior damage to Stanford buildings, slides (approx. 180) of damage to and repairs done at the museum, personal accounts from university staff and students, miscellaneous university newsletters with quake-related stories, and special editions of assorted newspapers.
Access Terms
Earthquakes --California --Personal narratives.; Earthquakes--California--Loma Prieta Region.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Press releases from the Stanford University News Service, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notices, newsletters, news articles with related photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal accounts A-K (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Personal accounts L-Z (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs by Linda Long of interior and exterior damage to Stanford buildings (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of interior and exterior damage: b/w contact sheets by Visual Arts Services and color negatives of photos by Phil Leighton (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photos of Math/CS library and university libraries in general (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photos, Special Collections department (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photos, Stanford Housing Center (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photos, miscellaneous negatives (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to parents, alumni and friends from Donald Kennedy, Dec. 1, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newspapers
    - Wall Street Journal, Oct. 19, 1989 (Box 2)
    - San Jose Mercury News, Morning Final, Oct. 18, 1989 (Box 2)
    - San Jose Mercury News, Oct. 19, 1989 (Box 2)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, Extra, Oct. 18, 1989 (Box 2)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, Oct. 19, 1989 (Box 2)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, Oct. 20, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Los Angeles Times, Special Report, Oct. 20, 1989 (Box 2)
    - [Stanford] Campus Report, Oct. 18 and Oct. 19, 1989 (Box 2)
    - "CLASS Forum," Winter 1990 [Cooperative Library Agency for Systems and Services – includes image from SUL interior damage] (Box 2)
  - Slides (Box 3)